Carey Orr Cartoons
Carey Orr Cartoons
- Cartoons
  - 1916-1928
    - Don't let him out, he knows too much.", 1927; 1927.0033.Orr; A man in a KKK outfit is standing outside a prison door labeled "Cell of D.C. Stephenson ex- klan leader of Indiana - Sentenced to life imprisonment for murder." Signs outside the cell read: Solitary confinement cell," and "Don't talk to the prisoner." Papers on the floor read: Stephenson threats to divulge Klan scandals," and "Smuggled Stephenson letters." To the left a guard comes with keys to the cell that are labeled "Habeas corpus," and "Investigation of Stephenson charges." To the left in the background peeking around the corner is a man labeled "Indiana Anti-Saloon league" who says, "I hate investigations too!"C. Stephenson was the Grand Dragon of the Indiana Klan. He was tried for the kidnapping and rape of his secretary who then died of poisoning. The scandal destroyed the image of the KKK as upholders of law and order, and special protector of the virtue of white women. Preliminary sketches for cartoon on verso. "He knows too much." Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 14)
    - The deluge., 1927; 1927.0034.Orr; In the sky are storm clouds labeled "Tunney" and "Dempsey." Money is raining on top of "Pickard" and the mounds of cash is labeled "Gate receipts."Tunney and Jack Demsey fought for the title on September 22, 1927, in a ring set up in the center of Soldier's Field. About 150,000 witnessed the fight in which Tunney retained his title. $2,800,000 was earned in ticket sales under the promotion of Tex Rickard. Doodles on verso - man golfing. "league - politicians - immigrations - B...... - Boxing - Editors." Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune."3 cols am" on recto bottom." (Oversize 14)
    - A 'ell of a 'ole., 1927; 1927.0035.Orr; An elephant labeled "Republican party" is hiding in a trench labeled "Prohibition neutrality." Missiles are flying overhead between the "wets" and "drys." Behind the elephant is a bomb labeled "Borah" with a lit fuse."sketches for unknown cartoon on verso. "3 cols Monday am." on recto bottom edge. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 14)
    - Expressing his sympathy., 1927; 1927.0036.Orr; A man labeled "Sacco-Vanzetti Sympathizer" is shown carrying a lit bomb labeled "Appeal for Mercy." He's leaving the site of a home that is being blown up."April 15, 1920, a paymaster and guard were carrying a factor payroll of $15,776 through main street of South Braintree, MA. A gang of five opened fire on them and sped away with the payroll. The two were mortally wounded. Nicola Sacco and Bartolomeo Vanzetti fell into a police trap set for the Braintree murders. The did not fare well in the political system because of their broken English, Italians as character witnesses and not taking the stand for their own defense. After lengthy appeals, they were sentenced to death on April 9, 1927. However, the dignity and words of the two had turned them into powerful symbols of social justice for many throughout the world. The governor considered clemency for them, however, they were executed on August 23, 1927. The workings of democracy seemed flawed to many Americans with this event. Paper overlay: copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 14)
    - The executioner and the death chair., 1927; 1927.0037.Orr; In a "Court of Justice" a man labeled "Organized Terrorist" is holding a piece of paper labeled "Junkman killing." His hand is dripping with blood. He is standing behind the "Witness chair" that has a lit bomb under it labeled "Death threat." Approaching the chair is a man labeled "Junkman murder witness."sketch for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune."3 cols am" written on recto bottom edge." (Oversize 14)
    - titled, but title has been cut through at the top and unable to read", 1927; 1927.0038.Orr; A roller coaster labeled "Father time's scenic railway" is shown with several high points which keep progressing in height. The points are labeled: Jan 1,"Lincoln's birthday," St. Valentines Day,"Washington's Birthday,"Easter,"July 4th,"Halloween,"Nov 11th," and "Thanksgiving." The last point and highest is labeled "Christmas." The car going to the end of the ride passes "Father time getting ready to punch another year out of our ticket." cols Tuesday am." written on recto bottom. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 14)
    - Fattening up., 1927; 1927.0039.Orr; Cartoon in two panels: 1. A scrawny turkey labeled "business Conditions" is standing next to a "Businessman" who scratches his head and says, "He must have the pip or something." The scene is titled "The bird we were so worried about last summer." 2. An enormous turkey labeled "Improved business conditions" now stands in front of the man who says, "Looks like a wonderful Thanksgiving after all."overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 14)
    - A few more feathers and he'll soon be flying., 1927; 1927.0040.Orr; A man is standing in a bird's nest with feathers attached to his shoulders. He is labeled "American Public" and the broken egg shell beneath him is labeled "Airplane invention U.S.A." The feathers on his back are labeled "Lindbergh triumph,"Chamberlin-Levine accomplishment,"Maitland-Hegenberber success,"Byrd-Acosta flight,"Growing confidence in flying." The man says as he prepares to dive out of the next "I almost believe I could do it." The clouds in the air form the words "Travel by air."sketches for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 14)
    - Fighting for the reins., 1927; 1927.0041.Orr; A large boy labeled "Big Nations" is standing in a wagon labeled"The World's destiny" that is being pulled by a saw horse as a horse. The saw horse is labeled "League of Nations." Several boys labeled "Little nations" are trying to pull the "big nations" out of the wagon. The wagon is headed towards "Utopia."sketches for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune."3 cols am" written on recto bottom edge." (Oversize 14)
    - Fine fishin' but -, 1927; 1927.0042. Orr; A donkey in a row boat labeled "Democratic Party" sits with his fishing line tangled all over him. The line is labeled "Wet and dry snarl." The water is labeled "Farm dissatisfaction and fish labeled "Votes" are jumping in the water."doodles for unknown drawing on verso. "Prohibition,"China." Navy" Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 14)
    - Following each other around and getting no place., 1927; 1927.0043.Orr; A group of trees is labeled "Political woods - unsolved problems - crime - prohibition- farm - Mexico - local." Going around the trees in circles are two men. One man holds a sign that says "Politics - depending entirely upon public sentiment for guidance." The other man holds a sign that says "Public - depending entirely upon the politicians for guidance."sketches for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 14)
    - Gathering at the carcass., 1927; 1927.0044.Orr; A wolf labeled "Japan" growls at a bear labeled "Russia" as it approaches a mound of bones labeled "Poor old China,"Manchuria," and "Chinese Disunion." A group of vultures are sitting on a tree branch labeled "European powers" in the background. To the left background is a lion labeled "England."doodles for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 14)
    - Going to be hard to pass up., 1927; 1927.0045.Orr; Sitting up on a tree branch is a large turkey labeled "1928 Hopes." Beneath it is a barrel labeled "Wet Platform" and an axe labeled "Volstead repeal." In the background, a donkey labeled "Dem" is in tattered clothing and harrying a hobo stick that is labeled "Eight years of Starvation."overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune."3 cols am" written on recto bottom edge." (Oversize 14)
    - Gun shy - a good dog till the shooting starts., 1927; 1927.0046.Orr; A hunter labeled "European interests" is firing his gun into a woods labeled "Trouble in China," and "Chinese bolshevism." Bears can be seen in the background growling. Running from the hunter in the opposite direction is a dog labeled "Europe's League of Nations."sketches for unknown drawing on verso. "Can't answer the call." "...comes of mixing his drinks."League of Nations." Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 14)
    - Gimme a lift, Mister!", 1927; 1927.0047.Orr; An enormous man labeled "Gas Tax" is pulling a roller labeled "Hard roads for big land owners with political pull." He tries to get into the back of a small auto labeled "City flivver owner." The license plate of the auto is labeled "Illinois auto license tax." In the background behind a stone wall is a man labeled "Big land owner." A large billboard reads "For sale Country estate - per acre - -$150.00- which is crossed out- $1,000.00."overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." Preliminary sketches for cartoon on verso." (Oversize 14)
    - Getting hotter and hotter and he doesn't know how to turn it off., 1927; 1927.0048.Orr; A man labeled "China" is ironing a shirt labeled "Chinese problems." The iron is labeled "War" and the electrical cord is labeled "Red Influence." The electrical lines outside are labeled "Chinese hook-up with Moscow."sketches for cartoon on verso. Torn paper overlay: ....1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 14)
    - Going to take some measurements, 1927; 1927.0049.Orr; On the ground to the far right is a large Santa Claus labeled "German debts" who is getting his girth measured. Up on the roof of a house are men labeled "Financial experts" who are measuring the opening of the chimney labeled "German resources." Looking out a window of the house is a person labeled "France" who holds a large stocking labeled "French wants."sketch for unknown drawing on verso. (Oversize 14)
    - Getting tired of his role., 1927; 1927.0050.Orr; Two men are in an elephant costume labeled "Republican party leadership." The man in the rear is labeled "Western Republicans" and he says to "Eastern Republicans,"Say, wait a minute! Let's trade places for awhile!"filled with cartoon ideas and a few preliminary sketches and doodles. (Oversize 14)
    - Getting nearer and nearer., 1927; 1927.0051.Orr; A large barrel labeled "Wet and Dry Issue" is rolling down a hill and has just crashed through a fence labeled "Party fences." Men are in the foreground running away and labeled "Ducking and dodging politicians."doodle for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 14)
    - Gone about far enough., 1927; 1927.0052.Orr; A man labeled "China" is carrying a sword with blood dripping labeled "Anti-foreign riots." Behind him a man labeled "Bolsheviks" is pushing him into a bayonet labeled "U.S."sketches for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 14)
    - Gangway!", 1927; 1927.0053.Orr; Uncle Sam is approaching the gang plank of a ship labeled "U.S. Gunboat." He carries a flag that is labeled "Protection of American lives and property the world over," in one hand and in the other a gun labeled "Nationalism." Standing on the dock are four people who are trying to stop Uncle Sam from entering the boat. They are labeled: Pacifist school teacher, "Professional pacifist," and "Pacifist college professor."sketches for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 14)
    - Gettin' het up., 1927; 1927.0054.Orr; Uncle Sam is taking off his clothes and perspiring because his steam register is pumping out heat. The register is labeled "U.S. Mexico crisis." In the basement the furnace is labeled "Mexico" and a man is shoveling coal labeled "Pres. Calles' anti-American policies." The cartoon is in the shape of North America with U.S. on the first floor with Uncle Sam and the basement is Mexico."sketches for unknown cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 14)
    - Hard times for the pessimist., 1927; 1927.0055.Orr; Cartoon in four panels: The scenes involve a man labeled "Pessimist" who is talking to a miner labeled "Business." 1: The miner holds a large piece of gold labeled "1922 prosperity" that he has gotten from the "U.S. Industrial gold field." The pessimist says, "Too bad we can't find more like it!" The scene is labeled "Back in 1922 - the beginning of our present era of prosperity." 2. The miner pulls out another piece of gold labeled "More prosperity." The pessimist says, "Too bad it won't last!" The scene is labeled "1923 & 1924." 3, The miner pulls out another piece of gold labeled "More and more prosperity." The pessimist says, "It's too good to last much longer!" The scene is labeled "1925 & 26." 4. The miner is pulling out another piece of gold labeled "Prospects for 1928" from the mine labeled "Permanent prosperity." The pessimist has been knocked over and says, "It can't last!" The scene is labeled "1927." cols am" written on recto bottom. Verso has a stamp that reads: Received 1928 Jan 3 am 11 56, Engraving dept. Chicago Tribune." Preliminary sketches to unknown drawings on verso. "World Fair." Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 14)
    - His Christmas stocking., 1927; 1927.0056.Orr; A woman sitting on a rocking chair is knitting a large stocking that overs most of the globe. She is labeled "Public" and knits from a large ball of yarn labeled "500 Million dollars Christmas savings." Uncle Sam is waving to Santa Claus at the "North Pole" and calls, "Yo-Ho-O, Santy!" cols am" written on recto bottom edge. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 14)
    - His escort., 1927; 1927.0057.Orr; A new year baby with a sash labeled "1928" is walking down the street crying and carrying a sign labeled "The coming 'Happy New Year.'" Behind him walking with a pack of dogs is a man labeled "Anti-Saloon league." He carries a billy stick labeled "Injunction." The dogs are labeled "18th Amendment,"Volsteadism," and "Dry snoopers." He says to the baby, "Just one false move and - -"sketches for unknown drawings on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune."3 cols am" written on recto bottom edge." (Oversize 14)
    - He seems to sleep much better with a gun under his pillow., 1927; 1927.0058.Orr; Cartoon in two panels: !. A colonial man is sitting in bed with his hand to his ear. He is labeled "Public excitement over politics." The room is labeled "Our political household." The text to the scene is: There was a time when the least noise about the house disturbed him - " 2. The text continues, " - but that was before he was so well protected." A man is fast asleep with his head on a pillow labeled "Public lassitude." Under his pillow are pistols that are labeled "Direct primary,"Right to vote,"Women suffrage,"Direction election of Senators," and "Public Safeguards." Two burglars labeled "Political crooks" are in the room with crowbars and opening drawers with money."sketches for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 14)
    - His favorite pastime., 1927; 1927.0059.Orr; A lion labeled "England" is roaring and crying as a man labeled "Soviet Russia" is tying knots in his tail. The knots are labeled "China,"India" and Anything to worry England."overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 14)
    - He'll put his foot in something yet., 1927; 1927.0060.Orr; A large bear labeled "Soviet Russia" has avoided bear traps labeled "War with Italy," and "War with England." The bear's mouth is watering as it looks at the bait labeled "Control of Manchuria" inside the trap labeled "War with Japan."sketches for cartoon on verso. Paper copyright: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 14)
    - Helping China remove the millstone from his neck., 1927; 1927.0061.Orr; A man labeled "China" has a millstone around his neck labeled "Unequal treaties - extraterritoriality." His head is being held on a chopping block by a man labeled "Russia." The axe "Russia" holds is labeled "Red doctrines.": exemption from the application or jurisdiction of local law or tribunals. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." Preliminary sketches for cartoon on verso." (Oversize 14)
    - How about next year's crop?, 1927; 1927.0062.Orr; A man in a sombrero labeled "Mexico" is cutting down a tree labeled "American investments in Mexico." The axe he is using is labeled "Confiscation." The fruit in the tree are bags of money labeled "Profits."Mexico" says, "Too much of the fruit is falling on his side of the fence - I'll just take the whole tree." Scattered on the ground are applies labeled "Wealth for Mexico." In the background behind a fence is the shadow of Uncle Sam carrying a full bushel basket."sketches for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 14)
    - He wants to let the outside world in on it., 1927; 1927.0063.Orr; A man labeled "Interests opposed stands at a wall labeled "Immigration Wall." He is sawing it down with a saw labeled "Political Influence." Behind him are bags of money labeled "High wages," and "America standards of living" in mounds labeled "American prosperity built up under immigration restriction."sketches for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 14)
    - Heading straight for the rocks again., 1927; 1927.0064.Orr; A woman labeled "Lorelei pacifism" is sitting on a rocky shore playing a harp. The rock she is sitting on is labeled "Naval disarmament." Other rocks on the shore are labeled "British diplomacy," and "Japan." The mast of a ship is in the water by the shore and labeled "Harding disaster," with a flag that is labeled "U.S. Naval Supremacy." In the distance is a large ship labeled "U.S. Navy."Coolidge" is at the helm. On board is Uncle Sam who yells, "Port your helm!" It is towing another ship labeled "Hawaiian naval base," A sign in the background points to Naval preparedness."sketches for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 14)
    - How France keeps going., 1927; 1927.0065.Orr; A man is sitting on a cart labeled "France" carrying bags labeled "Financial burdens," and "New Loans." The emaciated horse pulling the cart is labeled "France's creditors." The man has a beet labeled "Promises to pay war debts" attached to a long pole that is used to entice the horse. The man says, "I never have to feed him."sketches for cartoon and unknown cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 14)
    - Handing each other a laugh., 1927; 1927.0066.Orr; Two men are standing at their backyard fence each laughing at the other's scarecrow. In the foreground is an "Eighteenth Amendment scarecrow." It is surrounded with crows labeled "Volstead violators," and "Bootleggers." In the distance is a "League of nations Scarecrow" that is surrounded by crows labeled "Same old militarism,"War in China, " and "War scares." The men standing at the fence laughing at each other are Uncle Sam and "Europe."sketches for unknown cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 14)
    - Huntin' bait., 1927; 1927.0067.Orr; A fisherman labeled "Cal" is holding his fishing pole and looking under a rock for some bait. His bait pail is labeled "Solution of farm troubles" and is empty. In the background is an elephant labeled "G.O.P" who is turning over rocks looking for bait. Swimming in the water in the foreground is a large fish labeled "Farm vote."doodles for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 14)
    - The harvest., 1927; 1927.0068.Orr; Cartoon in two panels: 1. A man labeled "Russia" is sowing seeds labeled "Bolshevism thistles" with "Class hatred" in "Europe." 2. "Russia" is now getting his hands pricked by thistles labeled "England,"France,"Germany,"Poland,"Italy,"China," and "Japan." the garden is labeled "Hatred of Russia."overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." Preliminary sketches for cartoon on verso." (Oversize 14)
    - Hang on to your barrel, Uncle!", 1927; 1927.0069.Orr; Comic in three panels: 1. Uncle Sam is shown carrying a large ship labeled "World's potential biggest navy" into a "Washington naval disarmament conference." 2. Uncle Sam is shown walking out of the conference with no clothes and a barrel around him labeled "Ruined Navy." 3. Uncle Sam is wearing the barrel labeled "What's left of our Navy " to "Further naval disarmament - Geneva conference."doodles for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 14)
    - His annual nip!, 1927; 1927.0070.Orr; Uncle Sam is standing with a small glass in front of a large barrel labeled "Spirit of 76 - brewed July 4, 1776, by ...signatures of those on the Declaration of Independence appear on the barrel Barreled by G. Washington." Next to the barrel is a broken jug labeled "Old fashioned 4th of July spree." Rockets are going off in the background and Uncle Sam says, "I still get a great kick out of it."sketches for unknown drawing on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 14)
    - He dared to criticize., 1927; 1927.0071.Orr; Standing on the end of a gang plank labeled "U.S. Navy" is a man labeled "Admiral Magruder." He is blind folded and has his hands tied behind his back. At the other end of the plank is a pirate labeled "politicians." A bucket of "Navy Red tape," Waste," and "inefficiency" is in the foreground. "sketches for cartoon on verso. "McNidell charges."Mitchell trying to help the navy."Barnacles." Paper overlay: Copyright, "1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 14)
    - Encouraging those international bad boys., 1927; 1927.0072.Orr; Uncle Sam is standing outside a home where the gate is labeled "U.S. Interests." Windows have been broken on the home and junk thrown at it. Uncle Sam has a switch in his hand and he is being stopped by "Senator Borah and followers." Standing outside the gate are three boys labeled "Chinese Bandits,"Mexico," and "Nicaragua Rebels." They have sling shots in their hands and are standing amid trash. "Mexico" says to the other two boys, "Go as far as you like, fellers - Borah will protect us."overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 15)
    - It'll soon be time for Father to do his shopping., 1927; 1927.0073.Orr; Cartoon in 5 panels: 1. A man is sitting in a chair reading his paper and says, "Say Helen, d'you know Christmas is almost here? We'd better be doing our shopping!" Helen says, "Well, bless my soul! Where have you been for the last month? My shopping is all done!" 2. Helen continues, "--and I'll bet you haven't even bought a present for me yet!" The man replies, "I have too!" 3. Helen asks, "What did you buy me?" Father is now laughing in his chair and replies, "Ha! Ha! Don't you wish you knew?" 4. Father is now getting on his coat. Helen asks, "Is it something gran-nd?" Father replies, "I'll tell the world it's gran-nd!" 5. The man is now seen outside worried and perspiring saying, "Something gran-nd? Let's see - I've got to buy her something gran-nd! M-M-M $$$$ -"of preliminary sketch for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1927, by The Chicago Tribune."3 cols am" on recto bottom edge." (Oversize 15)